hey everyone welcome to another lesson
in this tosca automation course today we
are going to talk about the requirements
section in tosca and how you can
basically organize create
and risk way your requirements using
tosca right
so requirements is an important part of
any development life cycle because
that's the first step um which you need
to perform in order to
start with the development life cycle
right
so we need to collect the business
requirements from the clients or
customers and
then we need to create different
documents which then are passed over to
the developers and testers who in
turn they will design the solution the
testers would
then create the test cases and then um
the manual and automation test cycle
will begin right
so the whole life cycle is basically
dependent on these requirements and once
we get these requirements in the form of
business specification documents or um
in some other tools like jira or quality
center right then
we can
design our test cases based on these
requirements
okay now tosca has also got a section
where you can define your requirements
you can organize your requirements you
can structure them
and also you can
basically do a risk analysis of all
these requirements right and these can
be linked to different sections of tosca
as well like the execution list uh the
test cases section right the test case
design section so we'll talk about it
in this particular video
so
as i said tosca allows us to set up the
requirements basically structure them we
can create different folders different
requirement sets
and then it also allows us to risk weigh
them right so we'll see what is a risk
weight but it's basically a risk
analysis of how your business will be
affected if this requirement coverage is
not 100
right or
some requirements are not covered in
your testing right so that's basically
the risk analysis which tosca provides
in different ways
okay
now requirements can be linked to other
sections of tosca as i was talking about
you can
link it to the test case design section
you can link it to the test cases
section
and also the execution list right so if
you have not talked about i think the
test case design and execution list we
are going to talk about it but we have
seen how to create a test case right and
we'll see how we can link them uh to
your requirements um in tosca
the requirement sets okay
they are basically
um another folder structure you can see
which contains groups of different
requirements okay so you have to create
a requirement set within the
requirements section and then you can
put your requirements inside this
requirement set okay we'll see that how
you can create that
and
it can represent different aspects of
application right so which means uh you
can design them as per your
as per how your application is formed
okay so if you want you can
um
represent different aspects like front
and back and and non-functional
requirements or you can uh also
represent in the form of testing views
okay so which means you can um
you can segregate them between the
regression tests or smoke tests or some
other sprint release cycles okay so you
can design it as you per your wish or as
per your application
but
you have to basically group them
into different requirements and then
requirements into different requirements
sets okay
now talking about uh risk weight in um
tosca so there are basically two ways to
weight the requirements right
so one is called the basic weighting um
and
this allows us to assign values to each
requirement between a scale of one to
five although you can
assign any value between one to ten
but the best practice in tosca it says
that
you
assign a value between one to five okay
so one being the lowest and five being
the highest so if your business
requirement is very critical then you
will assign a value five if you think
that it is not very critical you can
assign somewhere between one two three
okay so that depends on your analysis
it's just a way of um
analyzing the requirements uh with the
business and then uh putting a weight on
that particular requirement in tosca
right so it's a very uh linear way of
risk weighing your requirement in tosca
which is called the basic paying okay
now coming to a complex wing
where
it uses two values to basically
calculate uh what will be the weight of
this particular requirement okay and
these two values are damage class and
frequency class okay
so what is damage class um it is
basically the potential financial loss
okay associated with the failure of that
particular requirement so if the
requirement fails then what will be the
potential loss to your uh application
okay or your business financial
right
so
that's called the damage class and then
there is frequency class which basically
means um how frequently that particular
feature or functioning is being used in
your application right so how critical
it is to the users
so that's the frequency class
um now you can assign
a value similar to what we are doing in
the other weighing method so it will be
basically a one to five right any value
between one to five
um and the calculation of weight as you
can see here is 2 to the power of
frequency class
multiplied into 2 to the power of damage
class right so that's how this complex
weight is calculated
um now it is dependent on or it is
relative to other requirements right or
it could be relative to uh the complete
requirement set okay
so we'll see all of these how you can do
that in tosca right but this is a basic
overview of
how tosca helps you
to
create your requirements to structure
them and then to do a risk analysis
basically
so now let's see how we can add
requirements in tosca okay
so i am currently in the requirements
section as you can see
uh and we have already seen how we can
add test cases right so there is already
a section called requirements in tosca
now
either you can go directly into the
folder or you can also go here on the
top menu where you will see requirements
and it will ask you or it will allow you
to create different folders and
different objects which are basically
uh requirements or requirement sets
right
so
this requirements is the parent folder
right under which you need to have um
different folders based on your
application requirements right so how
you organize them how you structure them
is completely dependent on you okay and
your project
now um
the important thing
to note or to perform while you are in
the requirements section is to make sure
that you have got all these columns in
um when you are trying to create a
requirement right so there is frequency
class there is damage class that is
weight
there is contribution coverage specified
right but the important ones are
frequency class damage class and weight
right
now if some of the columns
are not present in in this section you
can always add any particular column
based on your need right so what you can
do is just go and right click on any
particular column header and
click on column chooser right so in
column chooser you will see here
there are different um column headers
which are present and you can add any of
them here right
so just click on it and it will add that
particular column into this particular
section right
so um
once you make sure that all the columns
are present now we can go ahead and add
our different folders right
so
let's consider
we have to add some requirements for
a website or an application which we
have seen earlier called source demo
right so it's basically
a demo website
which has been provided by the source
labs and it gives you some options to um
add your items into your cart or
basically a full ecommerce application
right we have seen this earlier we have
already designed the test cases and that
is the reason
i am creating requirements for that
particular application okay
so um right click on the parent
requirements folder and there you will
see
um you can create a folder you can
create a folder structure
you can also create a requirement set
now the best practice is always to
create different folders before you
create a requirement set although it's
not
necessary but it is recommended okay so
let's create a folder here
and this will contain all my uh
different requirements for this
particular application right now you can
name it um
as per your uh convenience but i will
just name it release okay
now
inside this release folder right
now i can create another folder called
sprint one
okay so say for example um i have
different sprints and i want to create
requirements for each sprint right so i
will create uh these different folders
and that is how you structure your
requirements inside tosca okay now
um i can create any number of subfolders
as i want but i can also create a
requirement set right so this
requirement set
is a group of different requirements
okay so
now you can create this requirement set
and
you will see it is created here and the
coverage is already hundred percent
right because
there are no requirements which we have
defined inside this requirement set okay
you can name it um as per your
convenience again right so you can name
it anything
but um i will name it
something called user actions
okay
now in user actions what i will do is i
will create my requirement right so once
you create a requirement set you will
get an option to create requirement
now inside this i will say
login right so that's one of my
requirements
and then
i will say
register
register right
or let's name it login user for better
clarity and then register user
right so these are different user
actions which a user might perform on my
particular application right so he will
go and register himself or he will go
and login himself right so these are two
broad categories of requirement okay
now let me create in the requirement set
and i will call it product
actions
right
now in this product actions um i can
have different requirements
uh say for example i will say filter
products right so this is one action
which a user will perform so i will have
different requirements for that
um i will say add products right so a
user will basically add um his products
into his cart
and then um
i will say
[Music]
search products right so
so these you can see um if you consider
e-commerce application these are the
different requirements which you can put
right so depending on your application
you have to define the requirement set
and the requirements based on that right
or if you have a document that's even
easier right you can directly put your
requirements as it is in tosca okay
now coming to the requirement set as you
can see there are three um
in this there are three requirements and
in this requirement there are two
requirements right currently as you can
see um it's basically very simple uh
it's simple weight which has been
assigned by default from tosca right so
the weight is one and one the
contribution is fifty percent coverage
is hundred um
the execution state is hundred because
we haven't executed it so once we
execute based on pass and failure this
execution state will change right
there is also relative weight uh which
means um relative to different
requirements in this requirement set the
weight is 50 and 50 because there are
two requirements right
then there is also a column called
required test cases so if you have
linked any test cases it will show it
here right
so these are the different columns um
there's also frequency class and damage
class but um we haven't
uh we are not going to use that in this
particular requirement set we'll use it
in a different requirement set okay
um you can always define a description
for your
particular requirement right so you can
say
requirement um
user should be
able to login
into
the application something like this
right which basically describes your
requirement what it is right so you give
a name you give a description and then
you give a wait
now login user is a very critical
functionality because um without logging
in the user cannot perform any other app
any
um any other functionality okay now um
let's look at the application itself for
which we are defining the requirements
right so this is basically the
application and as you can see um the
most important functionality of this
application is logging into the
application right without it um the user
basically cannot do anything else right
so
once he logs in then he can search for
products filter products and add the
products into the cart right so this
seems to be a very critical
functionality and if it doesn't doesn't
work
um
my business is going to be heavily
impacted right so that's how um you take
and vary your requirements right you put
a weight on your particular requirement
so
i will call or i will put a wait for
login user as five because i think it's
very critical for my application
for register user i can put it as three
right so i don't think that currently um
the register functionality
is so critical for my business right so
as you can see as you put a weight on
your requirement the contribution
changes right um the relative weight
changes okay so depending on the weight
um it will auto calculate your
contribution to this particular
requirement set okay
so since it has got a
more weight the contribution is more uh
it has got less fit so the contribution
is less
okay
now let's look at the other requirement
set which is basically the product right
um
so
let's go and login into this particular
application
and
let's talk about other requirements
right so i can
filter uh my requirements based on some
filter criteria right i can search for
different products here okay i can go
through each product and see what are
these products what i want to do
i can add my products into the cart
right so these are different
functionalities which i can see in this
application
now
similarly now i have to put a weight on
all of this right
now what i will do is i'm going to use
the frequency class and the damage class
right now we remember uh what i
explained about the frequency class so
how frequently this occurs right and
what will be the damage to the business
if this doesn't work right
so in here i see the add products is
very um
very critical to my business and damage
um is also very high if this
functionality doesn't work
right
filter products not so much right so i
will give it a three and three
and uh search products is still critical
right but um not as critical as maybe uh
adding products to cart right so this is
a basically basically a analysis um from
my understanding of the business
requirements right
um you can always um
refer to your documents you can always
discuss with the business analyst before
um
putting all these weights or even a
business analyst
can come in and
basically design this particular section
which is called the requirements section
right
so
as you can see um the frequency class
and damage class um
depending on this again the contribution
the weight changes automatically right
so this is
called the complex weight where uh tosca
decides the weight based on the
frequency and damage okay
so if you look at the calculation which
i talked earlier it is 2 to the power 3
into 2 to the power 3 right so basically
8 into 8 which is 64. similarly 2 to the
power of 5 into 2 to 12 5 is 1 0 2 4
right
so that's how the weight is calculated
based on what you provide values in the
frequency class and damage class
okay
so these are the two uh main um
ways of
risk weighting your different
requirements this is how you create your
requirements inside different
requirements sets and each requirement
set is again are divided into different
folders right
so
um this is how you basically
design your requirements in tosca
and the next step is to link your
requirements to different sections of
tosca right so that
um you can basically view your
requirements as a dashboard right so you
can see how much um execution is done on
each requirement how many test cases are
present right so
having test cases passed field so
everything
now um if you want to
link your requirements let me make it a
two window so that we can see it clearly
right
now here as you can see we have got test
cases okay
and we have got this source demo test
case okay
so
inside this um we have got this login
application test case right
so we don't have uh we haven't got many
test cases but there is a login
application test case so what i can do
simply is drag this test case and then i
will put it inside my login user
test
um or the requirement right login user
now
let me go back and put it in center so
that we can clear see clearly
as you can see
now login user has got one
one test case right which is linked to
this particular requirement
and as soon as you link it you will see
that it will have its own
coverage um and execution state as well
right so based on what you execute
or when you execute this test case this
execution state will change right
now coverage is hundred percent that is
because there is just one test case
here right
um if there are many test cases uh
depending on
whether those test cases have been
executed or not executed the coverage
and execution state will change right
um so you can link as many number of
test cases to your requirements based on
how many test cases
you have designed based on this
particular requirement similarly you can
do it for other requirements as well
right
now we can also
we can also uh link our test execution
list right and also our test case design
sheet since
i haven't spoken of these two sections
um i will
wait till we discuss about these two
sections and then i will show you how
you can link uh
these into your requirements right so
the process is pretty much the same
right so drag your testicles design
sheet or drag your execution list to the
particular requirement and
it will start kind of
collating everything into one particular
dashboard right
so
that is how tosca helps you to kind of
complete the whole life cycle right so
you have got the requirements you have
got
test cases you have got the execution
right you have got
different other sections where you can
basically design your test cases as well
right so the complete life cycle of
testing is covered in tosca
and the first part to it is the
requirement section
so we'll talk more about other sections
of tosca in coming up sessions
where we'll see
at test case design and also at
execution list